Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin autograph collection, 1833-2008.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen autograph collection
- Pershing, John J. Addressee: Major General William H. Carter Writer's location: In the Field, Mexico, January 9, 1917; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 1/4 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Content includes training of soldiers with pistols mounted on horses and his thoughts on universal service and the President of Mexico.
  Rudin # A-189
- Pittman, Isaac Addressee: Robert Paterson, Junior Writer's location: Bath, England, December 7, 1866; ALS 4.5" x 7.5"; Pages: 4 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Pitman states that shorthand is steadily advancing in England, although slowly as he had expected. (With a one page letter signed by his brother Benn Pitman).
  Rudin # A-190
- Pulitzer, Joseph Addressee: Governor David Hill Writer's location: New York, 10/20/1886; LS - 8vo; Pages: 3 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Pulitzer requests the participation of the National Guard at the dedication ceremony of the Statue of Liberty. Additionally, a 3 cent stamp preserved on a Cover commemorating the 100th anniversary of Pulitzer's birth is included. See also Bartholdi.
  Rudin # A-191
- Rabin, Yitzhak Addressee: John F. Cleary III Writer's location: Jerusalem, Israel, November 9, 1994; TLS - 8.5" x 11.75"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Rabin commenting on his receiving the Nobel Peace Prize.
  Rudin # A-192
- Rickover, Hiram G. Addressee: The Honorable John E. Moss Joint Committee on Atomic Energy Writer's location: At Sea, North Atlantic, March 3, 1975; TLS - 4to; Pages: 4 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Returning from sea trials of the nuclear powered aircraft carrier USS Nimitz, Rickover discusses the future of the nuclear carrier task force.
  Rudin # A-193
- Riker, Andrew, 1806; Doc S; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  Two page signed copy of Andrew Riker's will leaving his island to his sons. Also included is a four page Abstract of Title giving additional information about the heredity of Riker's Island.
  Rudin # M-92
- Rockwell, Norman Addressee: Mr. Julian Bach, Jr. Writer's location: New Rochelle, NY, May 16, 1939; TLS - 6" x 7"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Rockwell praises the beauty of American women.
  Rudin # A-194
- Rockwell, Norman Addressee: Miss. Mabel Saloomey Writer's location: n.p., January 8, 1950; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  He tells a student how to make a picture more realistic. Pictures should tell stories.
  Rudin # A-195
- Rockwell, Norman Addressee: Wm. Harold Martin Writer's location: Arlington, VT, July 23, 1951; TLS - 8vo; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  A letter responding to an idea for a painting that was sent to him.
  Rudin # A-196
- Rockwell, Norman Addressee: Mrs. Frank R. Dorlay Writer's location: Stockbridge, MA, July 10, 1956; TLS 6" x 8"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Letter of thanks for a model offer.
  Rudin # A-197
- Rockwell, Norman Addressee: Mr. Hudson Writer's location: Stockbridge, MA, November 21, 1970; TLS 5.75" x 7.75"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  States that he paints pictures of many important people from photographs taken by his photographer.
  Rudin # A-198
- Rockwell, Norman Addressee: Mr. Brian Mitton Writer's location: Stockbridge, MA, October 23, 1973; TLS 5.75" x 7.75"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Letter recommending attendance schools in order to learn to draw. Includes an original sketch of a dog.
  Rudin # A-199
- Rodgers, Richard Addressee: Miss. Jean Dalrymple Writer's location: New York, NY, May 15, 1978; TLS - 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Rodgers' personal statement of his own feelings on music.
  Rudin # A-200
- Rogers, Will Addressee: Edgar W. Cooley Writer's location: n.p., ca. Late 1925; TLS 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Defends charges that he is un-American. (With associated correspondence).
  Rudin # A-201
- Rogers, Will Writer's location: Hot Springs, FL, February 10, 1931; Silhouette 6.25" x 11.75" (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Full length silhouette signed. Includes Rogers stamps and envelopes.
  Rudin # A-202
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: Mr. Clayton Wheeler Writer's location: Eastport, ME, September 2, 1921; TLS 5" x 8"; Pages: 2 (Box 6, Folder 21a)
  "Franklin…had a mild case of poliomyelitis…but the doctors hope for a complete recovery." Also included in this file is an archive of Franklin Roosevelt - Clayton Wheeler letters, as well as Eleanor Roosevelt photos and stamps, and a Franklin Roosevelt Memorial Coin.
  Rudin # A-203
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: Mr. Sladdin Writer's location: New York, NY, October 25, 1932; TLS 6" x 7"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  "Paintings of myself are not my idea of joy!"
  Rudin # A-204
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: Mr. Lewis C. Reimann Writer's location: New York, December 9, 1932, January 10, 1933; TMS - 7.25" x 6.5" TLS - 6" x 6.25" TMS - 7.25" x 11"; Pages: 1 2 4 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  "I am dry personally...temperance must be preached..."; included is a copy of her 12/9/1932 radio speech about the girl of today and a copy of an "Excerpt from letter from Methodist Minister of Kansas" regarding drinking.
  Rudin # A-204A
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: Mr. Crowinshield Editor, Vanity Fair Writer's location: The White House Washington, November 9, 1935; TLS 6.25" x 9.25"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Declining an appointment to have a photograph taken. "I am not particularly fond of photographs".
  Rudin # A-205
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: "Tiny" (Mayris Chaney) Writer's location: Washington DC, April 17, 1945; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  "It was a great shock but I'm so glad there was no pain, no long illness".
  Rudin # A-206
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: "Uncle Fred" (Frederick Adrian Delano) Writer's location: New York City, December 4, 1945; TLS 6.0" x 7.0"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Eleanor indicates that FDR wanted a memorial similar to Thomas Jefferson.
  Rudin # A-207
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: Mr. Heuschkel Writer's location: New York, NY, October 13, 1949; TLS 6.0" x 7.0"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  "It is never enough to simply vote."
  Rudin # A-208
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: Mr. Salgo Writer's location: New York, NY, February 23, 1951; TLS - 8vo; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  FDR never allowed anyone to sign his name after he became President. With printed free-franked envelope.
  Rudin # A-209
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: Mr. Moore Writer's location: New York, NY, April 11, 1955; TLS - 7" x 6"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  "History should not be written from casual remarks...there is no necessity to lie ever...".
  Rudin # A-210
- Roosevelt, Eleanor Addressee: (Her children) Anna, James, Elliott, Franklin Jr. and John Writer's location: n.p., December 12, 1956; TLS - Quarto; Pages: 2 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  Eleanor writes to her children regarding the production of a play or motion picture based on the life of President Franklin D. Roosevelt.
  Rudin # A-210A
- Roosevelt, Theodore Jr. Addressee: Rabbi Stephen S. Wise Writer's location: Washington, D.C., October 16, 1921; TLS - 8" x 10.375"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 29a)
  "The right approach is "What can I do for the country. What can I put into the United States". Forty years before JFK said somewhat the same thing. As part of a letter supporting Joseph Levine as Bronx Borough President.
  Rudin # A-210B
- Rusk, Dean Addressee: Jim Bishop Writer's location: Athens, GA, April 19, 1973; TLS - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  His comments on the assassination of JFK.
  Rudin # A-211
- Rusk, Dean Addressee: Mr. John Bullard Writer's location: Athens. GA, June 15, 1992; TLS 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  Rusk states that it is untrue that civilian control tied the hands of the military, which prolonged the war.
  Rudin # A-212
- Russell, Bertrand Addressee: Mrs. Mitchison Writer's location: London S.W., November 9, 1924; ALS 5" x 7"; Pages: 4 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  Discusses his theories on raising children and on education.
  Rudin # A-213
- Russell, Bertrand Addressee: Ruth Frank Rosenwald Writer's location: Merioneth, December 30, 1961; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  Russell expresses his opposition to nuclear war.
  Rudin # A-214
- Sadat, Anwar Addressee: Milton J. Shapp Governor of Pennsylvania Writer's location: Cairo, Egypt, December 12, 1977; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Letter expressing efforts to bring peace and "to destroy the psychological barriers obstructing the way towards stability and peace". With cover letter from Ashraf Ghorbal, Ambassador.
  Rudin # A-215
- Sanger, Margaret Addressee: W.H. Perry Writer's location: New York, NY, September 7, 1923; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Asking for support to make a Middle Western Birth Control Conference a success.
  Rudin # A-216
- Sanger, Margaret Addressee: Mr. Donahue Writer's location: New York, NY, April 2, 1938; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Letter to a supporter summarizing the importance of making birth control available in all communities.
  Rudin # A-217
- Schweitzer, Albert Addressee: Robert S. McNamara Norman Cousins Writer's location: Lambarene Lambarene, ca. October, November 11, 1962; TMsS - 4to ALS - 4to; Pages: 1 3/4 2 3/4 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Two letters that express his views on atomic war.
  Rudin # A-218
- Selden, George B. Writer's location: Rochester, NY, November 5, 1895; Printed Patent 7.5" x 11.5"; Pages: 6 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  First United States Patent for gasoline driven car. See also Bell, Edison, Tesla and Wright for other patents.
  Rudin # A-219
- Shackleton, Ernest H. Addressee: Kennar, R.N. Writer's location: London S.W., August 8, 2007; TLS 8" x 10"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Replies to a letter from a fellow explorer and wishes for a successful expedition to discover the South Pole.
  Rudin # A-220
- Sheen, Bishop Fulton Addressee: William E. Dugan Writer's location: n.p., February 9, 1953; TLS 7.25"x10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  "Very often the kind acts of men in the commercial world go unrewarded; too often their good deeds are accepted as duties". See also JFK letter to Arthur Krock in collection #6844.
  Rudin # A-221
- Sherman, William T. Addressee: General Henry W. Halleck Writer's location: Head-Quarters Military Division of the Mississippi Kingston, GA, 5/22/1864; Autograph Telegram Signed - 4to; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Telegram giving intelligence of his movements during the first weeks of his march through Georgia.
  Rudin # A-222
- Sikorsky, Igor Writer's location: Bridgeport, CT, April 20, 1935; Typed Memorandum Signed - 4to; Pages: 7 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  A letter of consideration to the Collier Trophy Committee for the S-42 trans-oceanic flying boat to merit the highest award in the aircraft field. Included is a 2 page memorandum from I.I.Sikorsky.
  Rudin # A-223
- Smith, Samuel Francis Writer's location: n.p., 1832, October 1884; Autograph Stanzas 5" x 8"; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  The entire four stanzas of our National Hymn "America". (Plus a supposed fifth stanza).
  Rudin # A-224
- Stanton, Elizabeth Cady Addressee: Mrs. Underwood Writer's location: n.p. (Europe), April 13, 1887; ALS 5" x 8"; Pages: 3 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Stanton's expresses her feelings on the extremes of wealth and poverty as well as her thoughts on the roles of women.
  Rudin # A-225
- Stevens, John Paul Writer's location: n.p., June 22, 1905; Ms S 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 7 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  Dissenting opinion in the case of Bush v. Gore, signed by Justice John Paul Stevens.
  Rudin # A-227
- Stevenson, Adlai Addressee: Sister Mary Linus Writer's location: New York, March 18, 1965; TLS 8.5" x 10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  The practical reasons for studying history.
  Rudin # A-228
- Stone, Lucy Addressee: Mrs. Clark Writer's location: Dorchester, November 28, 1883; ALS - 8vo; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Wants churches to support suffrage of women.
  Rudin # A-229
- Sullivan, Anne Addressee: Thomas Henderson Writer's location: South Arcan, Muir of Ord, Ross-shire, September 1, 1932; TLS 9" x 7"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Sullivan reflects on the significance of her work, both for herself and for the larger cause of the handicapped. Accepts a fellowship from the teachers of Scotland.
  Rudin # A-230
- Teller, Edward Addressee: Mr. B.H. McGee Writer's location: Stanford, California, February 5, 1980; TLS - 8vo; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  Technology, the application of man's knowledge, is his best defense against arbitrary power.
  Rudin # A-231
- Tesla, Nikola Writer's location: United States Patent Office, November 5, 1901; Printed Patent 7.75" x 11.25"; Pages: 8 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  "Apparatus for Utilizing Effects Transmitted Through Natural Media" Patent. See also Bell, Edison, Selden and Wright for other patents.
  Rudin # A-232
- Tombaugh, Clyde, W. Addressee: Jerry Granat Writer's location: Las Cruces, New Mexico, February 20, 1981; TLS 8.5" x 11"; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Answers questions posed to him about the universe by Jerry Granat.
  Rudin # A-233
- Tombaugh, Clyde, W. Addressee: Mr. Fisher Writer's location: Mesilla Park, NM, June 12, 1995; ALS 6" x 9"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  "I do not think there is a 10th planet".
  Rudin # A-234
- Truman, Margaret Writer's location: Beaumont, TX, February 27, 1950; Signed Program 6" x 9"; Pages: 4 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  Signed cover of music recital program. (With a second unsigned program).
  Rudin # A-235
- Trumbull, Jonathan Addressee: Ezekiel Williams Commissary of Prisoners Writer's location: Lebanon, Conn., December 15, 1977; ALS 7.5" x 12"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  (see also William Wall letter dated 7/8/1780) Permit for a Captain to pass to Providence in exchange for Major Wall during the Revolution.
  Rudin # A-236
- Victoria, Queen of Great Britain Addressee: Sovereign Land grave of Hesse Homburg (Ferdinand) Writer's location: Windsor Castle, June 19, 1865; LS 7.5" x 9.5"; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Birth announcement of George V.
  Rudin # A-237
- Wall, William Addressee: Major Samuel White Writer's location: Providence, Rhode Island, July 8, 1780; ALS 7" x 11.5"; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  (see also Jonathon Trumbull letter dated 12/15/1777) About partnering in a vessel.
  Rudin # A-238
- Warhol, Andy Writer's location: n.p., n.d.; TMsS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Warhol's philosophy on subways and on ghetto space.
  Rudin # A-239
- Washington, Booker T. Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute Tuskegee, Alabama, January 9, 1895; TLS 8" x 5.25"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  Notice that card-playing is against the policy of Tuskegee Institute.
  Rudin # A-240
- Washington, Booker T. Addressee: John Uri Lloyd Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute Tuskegee, Alabama, May 25, 1900; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  Capitalization of the "N" in the word Negro.
  Rudin # A-241
- Washington, Booker T. Addressee: Franklin W. Hooper Mrs. A.J. Kaine Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute Tuskegee, Alabama, November 5, 1901, July 16, 1904; TLS 5.5" x 9.25"; Pages: 1 1 1/4 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  Considers speaking at Brooklyn Institute of the Arts (Hooper Letter); Mentions his controversial visit to the White House (Kaine Letter). Originally in the Forbes Collection.
  Rudin # A-242
- Washington, Booker T. Addressee: Rev. Charles D. Kreider Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute Tuskegee, Alabama, November 20, 1901; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  The girls that attend his school are not really willing to relocate north as useful opportunity is available to them in the south.
  Rudin # A-243
- Washington, Booker T. Addressee: George Bicknell Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute Tuskegee, Alabama, October 8, 1904; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  Entrance qualifications for students interested in applying to Tuskegee Institute.
  Rudin # A-244
- Washington, Booker T. Addressee: Frederic S. Hartzell Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute Tuskegee, Alabama, September 16, 1907; TLS 6" x 8.25"; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  Washington pays tribute to McKinley and his interest in the Negro people.
  Rudin # A-245
- Washington, Booker T. Addressee: Caroline Arabella Rankin Writer's location: Tuskegee Institute Tuskegee, Alabama, March 20, 1911; TLS - 4to; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  Washington asks for Rankin's frank impressions of the Institute.
  Rudin # A-246
- Watson, John B. Addressee: Henry Goddard Leach Editor, The Forum Writer's location: New York, September 20, 1928; TLS - Quarto; Pages: 2 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  "The idea of punishment is psychologically wrong."
  Rudin # A-246A
- Watt, James Addressee: Davies Giddy Writer's location: Heathfield, Birmingham, August 11, 1811; ALS - 4to; Pages: 1 3/4 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  Giving the recipe for making cloth waterproof.
  Rudin # A-247
- Weizmann, Chiam Addressee: Prof. Chaim Weizmann Mrs. Anita Engle-Berkoff Writer's location: Balleymoney, Co. Antrim London W.C. 1, October 6, 23, 1941; TLS-4to TLS-4to; Pages: 3 1 1/2 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  Weizmann discusses "the steps which ought to be taken to mobilize all Zionists...for the advancement of our aims in Palestine." With a strong letter to Weizmann of suggestion and support from S. McCoubrey.
  Rudin # A-248
- Willard, Frances E. Writer's location: n.p., n.d.; Ams - 4to Not Signed; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  "Every woman that lives is bound to find out what the best thing she can do, is!" ("Leaf out of a lecture").
  Rudin # A-249
- Walter Winchell, 1940's, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  A collection of correspondence, documents, telegrams, and newspaper clippings, all relating to his 1960 interview of Richard Nixon and to the "Confucius Say" phenomenon of the 1940's.
  Rudin # A-250
- Duke of Windsor - Edward the VIII Addressee: Philip Guedalla, Esq. Writer's location: Government House Nassau, February 15, 1943; TLS 7.25" x 10.5"; Pages: 3 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  Talks about BBC broadcasts, new issues of Bahamas stamps, has given up "all hope that those in power today will...ever assign me to a more important mission", and much more.
  Rudin # A-251
- Wright, Frank Lloyd Addressee: For Your questionnaire To the Record Writer's location: Taliesin West, March 13, 1954; Quarto; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  "It is my belief that the great Art of Architecture cannot be taught."
  Rudin # A-252
- Wright, Frank Lloyd Addressee: Mrs. Walter O. Forsman Writer's location: Taliesin West, January 29, 1957; Quarto; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  Replies to Mrs. Forsman about how he considers the display of pictures important and that he provides for them in his architectural designs. (With letter from Mrs. Forsman to Wright - Letter date 1/25/57).
  Rudin # A-253
- Wright, Orville Addressee: George F. Kuns Writer's location: Dayton, Ohio, December 10, 1925; 7.25"x10.5"; Pages: 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  States that none of the early machines (except the one for 1903) are still in existence. Mentions his glider flight of 1911. Includes photo.
  Rudin # A-254
- Wright, Orville Addressee: Wilbur and Orville Wright Writer's location: United States Patent Office, October 14, 1913; Printed Patent 7.25" x 11.25"; Pages: 14 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  Flying Machine Patent - 10/14/1913. See also Bell, Edison, Selden and Tesla for other patents.
  Rudin # A-255
- Wright, Orville, Postcard; Pages: 1 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  Color postcard of Wilbur and Orville Wright Memorial Beacon.
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Signed Books
Alone, by Richard Byrd.
Little America: Aerial Exploration in the Antarctic, the flight to the South Pole, by Richard Byrd.
My Life's History, by Grandma Moses.
The Deposition of Alexander G. Bell In The Suit Brought By The United States To Annul the Bell Patents, signed and addressed to Charles Swan.